<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lwxblog.github.io/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>I blog here.</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Web Spinners and Perceived Loading Speed</title>
	  <link>//web-spinners-and-perceived-loading-speed</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-03-15T08:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//web-spinners-and-perceived-loading-speed</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Recently I came across quite a prominent site that uses a gif spinner.</p>

<p>Spinners are usually used to indicate loading, and gives the user some feedback regarding the page, otherwise they may leave - thinking that the page failed to load. A gif spinner is just a gif that has some sort of animation that serves as feedback.</p>

<p>While the file size of the gif is relatively small, I cannot help but wonder why the site did not simply use a CSS spinner. It would definitely be faster and looks cleaner too, considering that the gif spinner looked out of place as well, I wonder what are the advantages except for maybe saving some development time by using some existing gifs on the internet.</p>

<p>I used to be tempted by gifs as well, because they can easily accomplish what might take forever (for someone like myself) to do in CSS. I am definitely not well-versed in CSS, and I have been trying to level up my styling skills. After I understood CSS a bit more, I cannot go back to using gifs, especially not for something as simple as a spinner.</p>

<h3 id="a-barebone-spinner-that-i-always-use">A barebone spinner that I always use</h3>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-html" data-lang="html">    <span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"spinner-container"</span><span class="nt">&gt;</span>
        <span class="nt">&lt;div</span> <span class="na">class=</span><span class="s">"spinner"</span><span class="nt">&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</span>
    <span class="nt">&lt;/div&gt;</span></code></pre></figure>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-css" data-lang="css"><span class="nc">.spinner-container</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="nl">display</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">flex</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">justify-content</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nb">center</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">margin-top</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">250px</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="p">}</span>

<span class="nc">.spinner</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="nl">width</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">55px</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">height</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">55px</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">border-radius</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">50%</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">border</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">3px</span> <span class="nb">solid</span> <span class="m">#ccc</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">border-right</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="m">3px</span> <span class="nb">solid</span> <span class="no">teal</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="nl">-webkit-animation</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">spin</span> <span class="m">0.7s</span> <span class="n">linear</span> <span class="n">infinite</span><span class="p">;</span>
<span class="p">}</span>


<span class="k">@-webkit-keyframes</span> <span class="n">spin</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="nt">0</span><span class="o">%</span> <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nl">-webkit-transform</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">rotate</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="m">0deg</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>

    <span class="nt">100</span><span class="o">%</span> <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nl">-webkit-transform</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">rotate</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="m">360deg</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Of course, one should always add in the default properties in addition to vendor-specific properties like -webkit, -moz, I leave that to you.</p>

<p>The effect is this:</p>
<div class="spinner-container">
        <div class="spinner"></div>
</div>
<style>
.spinner-container {
    display: flex;
    justify-content: center;
    margin-bottom: 20px;
}

.spinner {
    width: 55px;
    height: 55px;
    border-radius: 50%;
    border: 3px solid #ccc;
    border-right: 3px solid teal;
    -webkit-animation: spin 0.7s linear infinite;
}


@-webkit-keyframes spin {
    0% {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(0deg);
    }

    100% {
        -webkit-transform: rotate(360deg);
    }
}
</style>

<p>And we can make it spin faster or slower by changing the animation duration.</p>

<p>One interesting aspect I have discovered is that a shorter spinning duration does not mean it is perceived to be faster. There is a sweet spot that creates the optimal illusion of the data loading fast, which is in-between a fast and a slower spinning animation. Personally I like a 0.7s duration.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Covid-19 and Social Responsibility or Lack Thereof</title>
	  <link>//covid-19-and-social-responsibility-or-lack-thereof</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-03-13T08:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//covid-19-and-social-responsibility-or-lack-thereof</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>As Covid-19 spreads, the lack of social responsibility in Singapore is accentuated. While it has always bothered me, even before this highly infectious virus. The dangers of irresponsible behaviour has never been more apparent and detestable.</p>

<p>I am not saying that all Singaporeans lack civic mindedness, it is an indisputable fact that amongst us is a minority that pays no heed to personal hygenie and I suspect some takes pride in being unhygenic, mocking at the ones whom actually takes the situation seriously.</p>

<p>What prompted me to write about this was when I walked past my neighbour, who has been coughing quite badly for more than a week now, and could be under quarantine yet insists on smoking at the common area or going out with his friends, he <strong>deliberately</strong> coughed in my direction a couple of times. I strongly feel that he is trying to spread his virus to me.</p>

<h3 id="lets-take-a-step-back">Let’s take a step back</h3>

<p>Living in a HDB, I am no stranger to second-hand smoke coming from my neighbour who loves to smoke at the common area, his family likes to place their stuff at the shared space between our units. The sense of entitlement and their slow but definite encroaching was a telltale sign. They also love to burn incense that seeps into my house, causing me a literal headache.</p>

<p>I have tried to bear with them, and have never reported them for anything minor, but the haze from the incense that they were burning gave me breathing difficulties.</p>

<p>I eventually reported them to Town Council (this was before Covid-19 and the coughing incident), they were <em>advised</em> by the officers but nothing concrete was done. To this date, it is a matter of tolerance.</p>

<p>It might irk some to say this, but we are of quite different background. On one hand, they have a lot of gatherings with shady-looking individuals and even set out tables at the shared space to drink liquor in wee hours. Which is not just causing a disturbance but also very worrisome, as being intoxicated usually carries a fair amount of burden (colleteral damage).</p>

<p>To be fair, I have not always been under the opinion that they are troublemakers, but after a sudden visit from the police asking for assistance on locating my neighbour for an investigation and him hiding in his flat until he eventually relented and surrendered, coupled with my observation thus far (with adjustment for confirmation bias) - has led me to the impression that they are not pleasant people to say the least.</p>

<p>Another reason why there is no real action taken by the authorities might be that this could have something to do with religion. Since the burning of the incense, coupled with some very strange visitors going to their unit for what seems to be divine blessings and ringing of the bell all points towards some sort of religious beliefs. Which is a touchy subject in Singapore, a can of worms that no one likes to open. However, I am going to avoid commenting on the religious aspects.</p>

<p>Their actions reveal many deeper underlying issues in Singapore, and perhaps many other countries with social division. To be clear, my family and I are quite poor, and we are definitely in the middle-lower class range. Therefore, I am really glad that I live in Singapore, where if you work hard, you <em>can</em> actually climb out of poverty and build a better life. If you notice, you can broadly stratify people into two groups:</p>

<ol>
  <li>People who are striving for a better life</li>
  <li>People who are unwillingly to work/work hard</li>
</ol>

<p>For the perceptive ones, you may have already noticed this is a simple crabs in a bucket situation, and therefore crab mentality applies. Group 2 people will <em>always</em> try to pull people from Group 1 down - a bold statement, but makes logical sense.</p>

<h3 id="the-most-dangerous-man-is-the-one-with-nothing-to-lose">The most dangerous man is the one with nothing to lose.</h3>

<p>No matter how rich/influential one may be, you’re only human. Which means you are governed by biological limitations - i.e. illness, death. Covid-19 being a virus, with a relatively high fatality rate as compared to seasonal flu, brings out the worse in Group 2 people. It is, to them an opportunity to exert some control in their downhill life, by spreading the virus, no matter how rich or poor you are, you end up in a russian roulette. And if they lose, they have <em>very little to lose</em>.</p>

<p>This is why the first reaction of Group 1 people is to barricade themselves in their own world. Because of self-destructive behaviour from Group 2 that poses a real threat to society.</p>

<p>I feel that the world has always been this way, but only made even more apparent these days thanks to socmed. I would quote just two recent examples:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Hong Kong Riots (some would say protests but it’s my blog)</li>
  <li>Shincheonji - the South Korean church that spreads Covid-19 deliberately</li>
</ol>

<p>In the first example, it appears to be the HK SAR v The People of HK. But if one would dive deeper, you will find that there is actually a majority of HK citizens against the rioters/protestors. Which brings me to my point, the rioters are Group 2 people, unable to obtain a foothold in society, or a sufficiently comfortable position in life, which leads them to revolt since they have <em>nothing to lose</em>.</p>

<p>In the second example, it shows how easily a person carrying <em>a</em> virus can elect to infect many others and succeed relatively easily. I could also draw emphasis to the brainwashing of the cult-like religion, but I try to keep my blog religion-free.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-some-examples-of-irresponsible-behaviour-locally">What are some examples of irresponsible behaviour locally?</h3>

<p>Well, for one, in public transport like buses and trains which are the main mode of transport for many Singaporeans. I have witnessed sick people with a bad cough, openly coughing and sneezing without covering their mouth. I have also had a middle-aged man cut his nails and file them right in front of me, but I digress.</p>

<p>The main reason why these people are not practising proper personal hygenie is attributable to the crab mentality.</p>

<p>i.e. Since they are already sick, might as well bring down as many around them as possible.</p>

<p>How can we stop this kind of behaviour? I don’t know, someone please enlighten me.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-point-of-this-post">What is the point of this post?</h3>

<p>There isn’t any, this is simply a rant.</p>

<p>However, I might write more about the social division in Singapore and how irresponsible neighours can cause a nuisance leaving their victims to suffer in silence with very little recourse.</p>

<p>Perhaps after the current trial against the duo who alledgedly fatally assaulted an individual who has <a href="https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/courts-crime/yishun-death-alleged-assailant-says-he-had-intended-to-hand-victim-over-to">alledgedly been harrassing them for a prolonged period</a>.</p>

<p>What is interesting are the comments on socmed, where a lot of people empathizes with their predicament and feel that they are the true victims, and the only miscarriage of justice is that the deceased wasn’t stopped by law enforcement, leading to the unfortunate outcome.</p>

<p>I have some thoughts about this that I will write in a separate post.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Jekyll For Blogging</title>
	  <link>//jekyll-for-blogging</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-03-09T08:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//jekyll-for-blogging</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This blog is done in Jekyll. Which is why it seems only fitting to have the first post about Jekyll.</p>

<p>Truth be told, I had never heard of Jekyll until I googled for static site generators. What drew my attention was the fact that it’s written in Ruby. Having used Ruby on Rails before, I wanted to see the difference/similarities between Jekyll and RoR. I didn’t really know what to expect since I have never used a static site generator. But I had some baseline expectations:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Write markdown</li>
  <li>Parse it into html</li>
</ol>

<p>Jekyll met and exceeded my expectations. It somehow organizes all my posts and tags, allowing for easy searching and navigation. I have to dig more into how it’s implemented and the magic behind it. Color me impressed.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
